Guide to the Stacy C. Sherwood Fairfax City government collection, 1955-1987
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Stacy C. Sherwood Fairfax City government collection
1955-1987
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Stacy C. Sherwood
C0101
4.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
This collection contains documents on matters of Fairfax City planning and governance dating mostly from the years when Stacy Sherwood served as city councilman. Materials include official zoning board reports, city council meeting minutes, and correspondence between citizens and city officials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Stacy C. Sherwood in 1998.
Biographical Information
Stacy C. Sherwood grew up in Fairfax, Virginia and graduated from Fairfax High School in 1940. Sherwood spent much of his career working for the National Bank of Fairfax, where he rose from assistant cashier to senior vice president during the mid 1960s. Following in the footsteps of his father, who served as Fairfax Town Councilman for forty years, Sherwood served on the Fairfax Town Council from 1956-1960 and Fairfax City Council from 1960-1964. Most of the materials in this collection date from his tenure as Fairfax Town and City Councilman.
Scope and Content
This collection contains documents on matters of Fairfax City planning and governance dating mostly from the years when Stacy Sherwood served as city councilman. Materials include official zoning board reports, city council meeting minutes, and correspondence between citizens and city officials.
Series one is titled Subject Files. Among the documents featured in the series are letters on the nomination and election of Stacy C. Sherwood to the City Council of Fairfax. There are annual reports on the Town of Fairfax; Fairfax City Council meeting minutes from 1956-1963; zoning ordinance appeals and proposals. Also included are promotional pamphlets for annexation of surrounding territories. The series has financial records of Fairfax City expenditures and annual budgets. There is correspondence on transportation and utility planning; recommendations on city beautification and education. Finally there is information about the construction of George Mason College. The series is dated from 1955 to 1987 and is contained in 9 boxes.
Arrangement
Organized into one series.
Series 1: Subject Files, 1955-1987 (Boxes 1-9)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Sherwood, Stacy C.
Geographical Names:
Fairfax (Va.)--Politics and government.
Subjects:
City planning--Virginia--Fairfax.; Zoning--Virginia--Fairfax.
Contents List
- Series 1: Subject Files, 1955-1987
  Among the documents featured in the series are letters on the nomination and election of Stacy C. Sherwood to the City Council of Fairfax. There are annual reports on the Town of Fairfax; Fairfax City Council meeting minutes from 1956-1963; zoning ordinance appeals and proposals. Also included are promotional pamphlets for annexation of surrounding territories. The series has financial records of Fairfax City expenditures and annual budgets. There is correspondence on transportation and utility planning; recommendations on city beautification and education. Finally there is information about the construction of George Mason College.
  - Activities Report, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Analysis of Existing and Potential Revenue Sources, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annexation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Apartments, 1959 and 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beautification of Fairfax, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bills Paid, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Supervisors of Loudoun County versus Town of Fairfax, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Board of Zoning Appeals, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Bonded Debt of Virginia Cities, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Boys' Club, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Brochures, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Budget Report, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Calendars, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Campaign/Election, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - City Council versus BZA and Jim McKay Chevrolet, Incorporated, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - City Council of the City of Fairfax versus Board of Zoning Appeals of the City of Fairfax, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - City of Fairfax, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Civil Defense, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Fairfax City Council, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax City Council Meeting Minutes, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax City Schools, 1958-1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax City Times, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - General Fund Budget, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General Fund Budget, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - General Fund Budget, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - General Fund Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - General Fund Budget, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General Fund Budget, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - General Fund Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - General Fund Budget, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - General Fund Budget Report Fairfax (Town) City, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - General Fund Statement of Revenues, 1960-1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - George Mason University (GMU), 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Goose Creek Water Project, 1958-1961 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Highway Influence-Northern Virginia Region, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Items Related to Church, Bank and Unidentified Papers, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    1.4
  - Items Related to the City of Fairfax, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    1.1
  - Items Related to the National Capital Regional Planning Council (D.C.), 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    1.2
  - Items Related to Northern Virginia Planning, 1956-1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    1.3
  - Land Purchase, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mathy Property, 1957 and 1962 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Some Incomplete), 1960-1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Monthly Report Town of Fairfax, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Northern Virginia Region-Industry Present/Future, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Northern Virginia Regional Park Authority, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Northern Virginia Regional Planning and Economic Development Commission, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Notes, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ordinances, 1959-1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Ordinances, 1958-1963 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ordinances, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ordinances-Zoning, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Ordinances-Zoning, 1956-1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Parking Lot (Proposed), 1960s (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Personnel, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Planning Commission Recommendations, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Police Protection-Northern Virginia Region, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Public Libraries Analysis-Northern Virginia Region, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Real Estate Assessment, Taxes, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Reappointment to Board of Zoning Appeals, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Refuse Collection and Disposal System, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Report on Audit City of Fairfax, Virginia, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Report on Audit City of Fairfax, Virginia, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Report on Audit Town of Fairfax, Virginia, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Report on Audit Town of Fairfax, Virginia, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Report on Audit Town of Fairfax, Virginia, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Report on Audit Town of Fairfax, Virginia, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Report on Audit Town of Fairfax, Virginia, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Report on City of Fairfax, Virginia Municipal Water System, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Report on Town of Fairfax, Virginia Municipal Water System, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Report on Town of Fairfax, Virginia Municipal Water System, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Report on Town of Fairfax, Virginia Municipal Water System, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Sewage Treatment Plant, 1952-1957 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Statements of Cash Receipts and Disbursements Fairfax (Town) City, 1956-1962 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Taxes, 1955-1963 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Transit and Traffic, 1957-1963 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Various Booklets Regarding Fairfax, D.C. and Northern Virginia, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    1.5
  - Water Department Budget Fairfax (Town) City, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Water Department Budget, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Water Department Budget Fairfax (Town) City, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Water Resources-Northern Virginia Region, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Water-Reston, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Water Revenue Fund, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Water Service, 1955-1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Water and Sewer Billing Report, 1956-1963 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Zoning City of Fairfax, Virginia, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)